# **Shane Pinnell**

Information Technology Management

email: shane.pinnell@gmail.com

web: shanepinnell.com twitter: @shane\_pinnell phone: (909) 581-2429

## **Summary of Qualifications**

Well rounded knowledge of Information Technology and how it relates to education stemming from over ten years of experience leveraging a diverse skill set including, but not limited to the following:

Networking

Server Management

Application support

Programming

Directory Services

VoIP administration

Database Administration

Workstation support

SAN management

# **Work Experience**

#### Assistant Director of Technology 09/2015 - Present: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

In addition to the duties of the IT Supervisor below, provide leadership and work collaboratively with all levels of staff and management to promote the effective use of technology in instruction. Work with leaders in education and participate in local, regional and larger groups to help foster technology innovation and growth. Research new trends and solutions to ensure safe, reliable, equitable access to information to promote learning objectives in support of the District's mission and vision.

#### IT Supervisor 04/2014 - 09/2015: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

Manage the operations of and supervise a 16 person IT department in a successful 1:1 program. Ensure that infrastructure is maintained and continuously improved to provide 24/7 learning opportunities for students. Manage a large WAN with redundant high speed links, disaster recovery site and campus wide WiFi. Provide training for IT staff to grow and develop professionally. Act as a bridge between the demands of education and the technical intricacies of IT.

#### Network Engineer 06/2013 - 04/2014: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

Played a key role in the successful implementation of a district wide 1:1 program providing Chromebooks to over 10,000 students. Ensured that infrastructure was in place to provide access to world class content for students. Continually worked to improve access, reliability and security of network resources. Provided technical and customer service guidance and resources to helpdesk and site based technicians.

#### IT Tech I 06/2006 - 06/2013: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

Configured, deployed, managed and maintained WAN/LAN networking hardware, domain controllers, servers, SAN, workstations and VOIP systems. Provided training on web based content/classroom management systems.

#### Functional Systems Administrator 11/1997 - 7/2002: USAF, Hickam AFB, HI

Desktop support and server maintenance, backups and report generation. Provided user training on enterprise applications and productivity tools.

### **Education**

**Azusa Pacific University, Azusa CA**B.S. Management Information Systems

Perris High School, Perris CA High School Diploma

### **Awards & Achievements**

Apr 2017 - ACSA Region XIX
Technology Admin of the Year

Jan 2016 - CETPA
Certified Chief Technology Officer